#### Contact

Tawick07@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/teresa-wick-58962275 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Healthcare

Clinical Research

Physicians

#### Certifications

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support (ACLS)

Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS)

CEN

Trauma Nursing Core Course (TNCC)

Registered Nurse

# Teresa Wick

Clinical Nurse Mentor at HOUSTON METHODIST HOSPITAL Katy, Texas

## Summary

Experienced Registered Nurse with a demonstrated history of over 13 years working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS), Emergency Medicine, Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN) Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Healthcare Management, and Healthcare. Strong healthcare services professional with a Masters of Science in Nursing Education from The University of Texas Arlington. Excited to see how I can help educate new nurses and continue to work at the bedside as I believe that is how educators stay connected.

## Experience

#### HOUSTON METHODIST HOSPITAL

Clinical Nurse Mentor

January 2017 - Present (3 years 5 months)

6565 Fannin St Houston Texas 77030

Bedside education of newly graduated nurses in the emergency department while maintaining hands on bedside skills

### **Houston Methodist**

**RN 11** 

October 2014 - January 2017 (2 years 4 months)

Houstion Methodist Sugar Land ER

Position responsable for comprehensive patient care, utilizing research and evidence-based practice in a team approach to advance the healthcare of those who enter the doors both patients and families. Oct 2014 to Present

Houston Methodist Sugar Land Emergency Room RN October 2014 - January 2017 (2 years 4 months)

Harris Health System

1 year

ER RN 2014 - 2015 (1 year)

ER RN 2014 - 2015 (1 year)

ER RN 2014 - 2015 (1 year)

Memorial Hermann Health System 6 years 9 months

Clinical Coordinator, RN III
October 2012 - February 2014 (1 year 5 months)
Emergency Room at Memorial City Medical Center

Position responsible for serving in a leadership role and as a clinical expert in the delivery and management of comprehensive patient care, utilizing research and evidence-based practice as necessary; for expertly caring for patients from multiple services/specialties, and for more complex diagnosis.

Partners in Caring Emergency Room Representative at Memorial City.

Partners in Caring is an employee partner-driven process that strives for the unique environment where patients, families, employee partners, physicians and all others who enter our doors know they are somewhere special.

Participant in Leadership Academy at Memorial City Emergency Room.

Charge Nurse, RN III
July 2012 - January 2014 (1 year 7 months)
Emergency Room at Memorial City Medical Center

Position responsible for collaborating with the physician and healthcare team in the delivery of patient care, utilizing the nursing process to facilitate the delivery of patient care.

Clinical Coordinator of Pre-Op/PACU/Endo June 2010 - July 2012 (2 years 2 months) Memorial Hermann Surgery Center Katy

Responsible for staffing the Pre-Op/PACU/Endo, managed nursing hours, supervised the pharmacy hours, helped manage OR start times, approved surgical procedures per ASC guidelines. Worked as a Pre-Op/PACU/Endo nurse, ran code team, appointed and monitored infection control and employee health teams.

Emergency Room RN June 2007 - July 2012 (5 years 2 months)

Memorial Hermann Southwest

Position responsible for collaborating with the physician and healthcare team in the delivery of patient care, utilizing the nursing process to facilitate the delivery of patient care.

City of Katy Emergency Medical Services EMT-B

October 2005 - December 2007 (2 years 3 months)

Katy Fire Department

Determined the appropriate level of EMS assistance required, dispatched units, and accurately documented information according to established procedures.

## Education

The University of Texas at Arlington
Masters, Nursing Education · (2017 - 2019)

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston Bachelor of Science in Nursing, BSN · (2005 - 2007)